<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on Alexey Smirnov</title>
    <link>https://smirnov-am.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on Alexey Smirnov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Alexey Smirnov 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 15:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://smirnov-am.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting keyphrases from texts: unsupervised algorithm TopicRank</title>
      <link>https://smirnov-am.github.io/keyphrases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smirnov-am.github.io/keyphrases/</guid>
      <description>Keyphrase extraction is the task of identifying single or multi-word expressions that represent the main topics of a document. There are 2 approaches to extract topics (and/or keyphrases) from a text: supervised and unsupervised.
Supervised approach This is a multi-label, multi-class classification algorithm, where following features can be used as an input:
 text converted to bag-of-words text is treated as a stream of vectors, which are pre-trained word embeddings  For bag-of-words linear SVM is a good classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-commerce recommendation systems: basket analysis.</title>
      <link>https://smirnov-am.github.io/basket-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 12:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smirnov-am.github.io/basket-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Once novelty recommendation systems are used now by more and more e-commerce sites to help customers find products to purchase. For e-commerce business owners these tools facilitate cross-sales.
Usage Amazon is one of the most prominent organizations that used recommendations to increase sales. According to fortune.com Amazon was able to increase sales by 29% in 2012 as a result of implementing recommendation system. 35% of Amazon’s revenue is generated by its recommendation engine (source).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>